<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Embracing the Challenges of Technology</title>
<link>./index.html</link>
<description></description>
<language>en-AU</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 20:48:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 20:48:38 -0600</pubDate>
<generator>http://thingamablog.sf.net</generator>
<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>

<item>
<title>The Haskell Spin Project</title>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;
  Goal:
&lt;/h3&gt;
To&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rusticcoder.blogspot.com/2012/07/spin-project.html&quot;&gt;create 
a spin&lt;/a&gt; tailored for Haskell.&amp;#160; A single point where a noob or expert 
can go to get access to the best tools and resources to be successful with 
Haskell.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Please leave me comments with suggestions for Haskell 
resources.&amp;#160; This might include but not be limited to applications, IDEs, 
IRC channels, blog sites, web sites, how to's, getting started, etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The 
spin will need to contain everything a noob or expert would need to be 
successful.</description>
<link>./archives/the-haskell-spin-project.html</link>
<guid>./archives/the-haskell-spin-project.html</guid>

<category>Haskell</category>

<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 19:14:06 -0500</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Spin Project</title>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;
  Goal:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  To create bootable DVDs (spins) tailored for specific tasks.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  What is a spin?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Spins are a bootable DVD, independent of your installed operating 
  system, tailored for various types of tasks via hand-picked applications 
  and customizations.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  How do you use a spin?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Using the ISO file provided for the spin, you can create a DVD that will 
  boot into the spin when you insert it into a computer and turn it on or 
  reboot.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  One thing to remember when you run a spin off of a DVD is that any 
  additional applications you install will not be there when you reboot 
  your computer - there isn't any way to work around this because you 
  cannot write out a bootable DVD. Additionally, any files you save will 
  be lost when you reboot because, it doesn't access your hard drive. When 
  using DVD bootable spins, you should always make sure you save your 
  files to an external device such as a flash drive or USB hard drive.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  Why use a spin?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  1. No fuss no muss, everything is pre-installed and working.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  2. Try something new or demo something, no-risk. Try out new software 
  without having to completely re-install your system.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  3. You can choose to run the spin without affecting your computer's hard 
  drive.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  What if I don't want to boot off a DVD?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  You can run the spin in a virtual environment. Since you will in fact be 
  running two operating systems on the same computer, make sure you have 
  enough RAM and at least a duo-core computer.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekyprojects.com/tutorials/how-to-run-an-iso-image-file-in-virtualbox/trackback/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How 
  to Run an ISO Image File in VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  What if I want to use my own environment?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  You can download the Zim notebook that contains all the specifications 
  for the bootable DVD.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  Zim? What if I just want the streight scoop?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  You can review the Zim notes in HTML format using your web browser.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Problem Statement:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Getting started with any technology can take a lot of time researching 
  the best tools, blogs, and available resources.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Solution:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Create a single point where a noob or expert can go to get access to the 
  best tools and resources to be successful with a specific technology.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Spin Examples:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Astronomy
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Game Server
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Language Specific spins; e.g. GoLang, Node.js, Haskell, Java, Closure, 
  Scala, JavaScript
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Media Server
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Music Editing
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Video Editing
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Robotics
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Purpose:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Each spin should be a grouping of tools to focus on a specific task. 
  This might include but not be limited to applications, IDEs, list of IRC 
  channels, list of blog sites, how to's, getting started, etc.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  The spin will contain everything a noob or expert would need to be 
  successful.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<link>./archives/the-spin-project.html</link>
<guid>./archives/the-spin-project.html</guid>

<category>Haskell</category>

<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 08:37:07 -0500</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>