<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Embracing the Challenges of Technology</title>
<link>./index.html</link>
<description></description>
<language>en-AU</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 20:52:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 20:52:57 -0600</pubDate>
<generator>http://thingamablog.sf.net</generator>
<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>

<item>
<title>Commenting and Documenting Code</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
      I rarely comment my own code. The code I work on is rarely commented by 
      my predecessors or fellow developers, and what is commented is rarely 
      helpful. I read the existing comments as a last resort. So now that I am 
      looking at doing more commenting of my code I need to ask the most 
      important question, why comment?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The code I write is generally readable. I use verbose variable names and 
      reading from beginning to end the code makes sense. What I've commented 
      in the past is descriptive overviews or commented sections of code that 
      are not very clear as to the intent or how it works with other processes.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      When I've been asked to add more verbose commenting, it is in order to 
      make the code clearer for others to understand or teach them 
      programming. The problem I have with this approach is since I understand 
      the code I don't know what the others do and don't understand about the 
      code. Who reads the code in the future can very so greatly as far as 
      skill set and experience that I end up over commenting the code. Instead 
      of working independently, and commenting for a uncertain future I would 
      prefer another developer take my code, comment it in their words and ask 
      me questions as they comment my code. The benefit I see to this approach 
      is it works as a code review, someone else learns the code as well as I, 
      and it is commented with a fresh pair of eyes. It's understood that 
      developers are bad at testing their own code, I feel the same is true 
      for commenting.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Back to the question of why comment? I'm looking toward doing more open 
      source development. Using open source for many years I've noticed the 
      best solutions with the most contributors are also the best documented. 
      When I come across a project with a interesting name but no 
      documentation or examples I quickly walk away from the project. I'm not 
      going to waste my time figuring out someone else's code just to find out 
      it is not the right solution for my purposes.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I'm going to build some libraries with the intent to benefit others. 
      Documentation is critical to make these libraries beneficial to others. 
      Additionally commenting the code allows me to take a step back and 
      review the working solution in order to make it better. Improve the 
      design, refactor to improve the usability and maintainability. For me 
      software development is a evolutionary process, I never get it right the 
      first time.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      When to comment? I feel the general consensus is I should just comment 
      as we go along. For me every new project is unique. Often involving new 
      techniques, designs, architectures, and processes. Because I am 
      experimenting and the code is evolving, I'm refactoring as I go along, 
      often development is more like a prototype then a product coming off the 
      assembly line, commenting too soon is counter productive. Once the code 
      is commented the feeling is it shouldn't change, it's finished. When the 
      projects done it is often off to the new project, no time to go back and 
      document.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I'm going to try to document more as I go along but I will make a effort 
      at the end of the project to revisit the comments before considering the 
      project done. As I comment at the end of the project I will take the 
      time to take a step back and review the working solution in order to 
      make it better. Improve the design, refactor to improve the usability 
      and maintainability.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      What should be commented is the most difficult. With the purpose of the 
      comments to help new people to the project and help myself when I come 
      back a year from now, comment verbosity needs to be taken into account.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Comments are not a programming instruction manual. If a developer does 
      not know the language, syntax, or semantics, their are plenty of good 
      resources the developer can turn to. Comments are not a description of 
      best practices or a soap box. Best practices should be project wide not 
      code specific, documented in a central location to be reviewed and 
      updated as necessary.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Comments detail why was the code was written.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Document how the code is to be used, what should this do from a design 
      perspective..
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I switched terms from comment to document. I feel there is a difference. 
      Comments are brief, infrequent, and to the point. Documentation is 
      verbose, out of the way from the code, and generally more helpful.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Comment as you need clarification, document for someone else who will 
      need clarification.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      What should be commented? Comment from a high level what is going on. 
      Comment local objects like functions, structures, enumerations, traits, 
      closures, etc. as needed. Comment variables in special cases. For local 
      objects they should be named in a way it is easy to determine its 
      purpose so comments are not necessary. Code fragments should be brief so 
      that if the name of a local variable is not clear, reading the code 
      should revel the purpose of the object. Comment anything that might 
      appear confusing, odd, or does not work in a standard expected way. And 
      generally comment as to why the nonstandard, confusing, or odd code was 
      not refactored.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      What should be documented? A overview description at the top of the file 
      and before shared objects like functions, structures, enumerations, 
      traits, closures, etc. explaining the purpose and detailing its expected 
      use, and any oddities to expect when using the object. Examples work 
      very well in documentation.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Where should this commenting and documenting be located?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      For me documentation starts at design. Whether it be cocktail napkin, 
      e-mail, verbal communication all the design needs to be brought together 
      into a coherent document. I take that design and slice it up, moving it 
      into the various areas of the code. This might be front end, back end, 
      middle tier, test cases, or supporting documents. When all is said and 
      done the original design document is no more and has been destroyed. I 
      do this for a few reasons. First, multiple copies of the documentation 
      become out of sync. Second, it is easier to keep the documentation up to 
      date and reference the documentation when it is close to the code, 
      rather then in a document in some obscure location. Third, all too often 
      someone who has been away from the project will grab the out of date 
      documentation, reinterpret it, and try to make changes which should not 
      be made.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      So as I alluded to the design documentation moves as the project 
      progresses but finally it must rest somewhere.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        At the highest level is the readme which has a high level project 
        overview, examples, how to install, and how to use the software.
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Documentation before the specific object is the object level overview.
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Specific code is documented as needed.
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        But lastly most of the design ends up in the automated test cases. 
        Test cases prove the code does what the design says it should do.
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The challenge is many individuals want a document they can read from 
      beginning to end and understand every detail of the project. My hope 
      would be that compiling the readmes along with the test case 
      documentation would provide a document suitable to understand the 
      project from beginning to end.
    &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<link>./archives/commenting-and-documenting-code.html</link>
<guid>./archives/commenting-and-documenting-code.html</guid>

<category>Software Development</category>

<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:53 -0600</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>